What if plastic recycling, in fact, does little to help the environment and instead serves the
interests of the same big oil interest groups that are destroying Earth's ecosystems?
Say it ain't so.
They got us again.
A new report titled The Fraud of Plastic Recycling from the Center for Climate Integrity reveals
that apparently the oil and plastics industries have deceptively promoted recycling as a sustainable
solution for over half a century, despite knowing that plastic recycling is not technically
or economically viable at scale.
I have wondered this because I'd be like, where's this going?
What are they doing when we do the recycling?
What does it do?
When you find out that the trash cans at the airport that say like plastic and food, there's
not separate bags.
Oh, you're exactly right.
Sometimes it'll go in the same thing.
It's all the same bag.
It just has like little holes.
Skimming.
If you haven't listened to the episode of my podcast, Small Doses, Side Effects of Climate
Change with the head of the Slow Factory, Celine Saman, check it out.
She puts us on a whole bunch of game and she just talks about the ways in which we have
been tricked and she calls it wish cycling.
Wish cycling is when you and your mind like, yeah, I'm putting this in the recycling bin because
I believe this is going to get recycled.
And it's like, nah, ma, it's not.
It's not.
We are, we are, we are.
We are.